Guide to the Rolfe Humphries Papers, 1940-1970
Department of Special Collections
Rolfe Humphries Papers,
1940-1970
Special Collections M0971
Humphries, Rolfe
.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of D.L. Merrill, 1998
Biography
American poet and translator of classics, notably Virgil's AENEID and Ovid's THE ART OF LOVE. A native of Philadelphia, he attended both Stanford and Amherst, and later taught at both universities as well as others. His poems were published both as collected works and individually in many journals. He loved horse races and baseball. He was living in Woodside, California, when he died.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, notes, clippings, photographs, and biographical material.
Access terms
American literature--20th century.
Container List
- Newspaper, Magazine Clippings 1959 - 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence - Death of Rolfe Humphries 1969, April 22 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence - personal 1955 - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence - personal 1960 - 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Estate Filings - legal 1969, May (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Kent State University Press Agreement for publication of "Wolfville Yarns of Alfred Henry Lewis" 1968, Jan 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Lists n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Ovid" sales flyer 1955, May 23 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Rolfe Humphries Family Photographs n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Poetry 1940 - 1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)